SUHAL VEMU

Senior software engineer

Bangalore KA IN | mob:9986768698 | mail:vemusuhal@gmail.com

Summary

I am Tech Enthusiast with 5 years of work experience in software development with industry domains ranging from services to product based companies. Have experience in building scalable yet customer tailored solutions, cloud hosted, highly available SAAS product.

Skills

AWS Cloud Services

Practitioner
compute-EC2, elastic beanstalk,
Lambda | Integration - api gateway,
SNS,SQS | content - S3 | Athena | DynamoDB
ECS | AWS Batch Jobs |
Mangement- CloudWatch,IAM, config

Database

Practitioner
MYSQL | amazon rds | dynamo db |
Postgresql

Other skills

Enthusiast
GraphQL | aws glue | Elastic search|
MEAN stack| Infrastructure Building
And maintenance | docker

Web Application Development

Practitioner
html5 | css | javascript | python
Django framework | angularJs | C++

Web Servers

Practitioner
Apache2 | Nginx

CI\CD Tools

Practitioner gitlab ci | aws ecs |git lab

Experience

Cropin Technology, Senior Software Engineer.

Feb 2018-Dec 2019

In this AgTech Startup, I have built the SmartRisk product from scratch(entire Backend) and PlotRisk Product. I work in Data platform team my main deliverables include building platforms, Data pipelines for data scientists to work on. I lead the team of 2 members who are working with me.

Smart Risk product:

A business solution for better credit assessment in predicting the crops health, yield, Soil analysis using satellite images with the help of machine learning and predictive Analytics.

PlotRisk Product:

It is an architecture where we deliver the images with high, medium and low growth area in terms of harvest produce in the given plot of the registered farmer with the help of satellite images.

Deliverables and Achievements:

- a. Designed of the overall architecture of the web application(SmartRisk) and plotrisk.
- b. Implemented of a robust set of services and APIs to power the web application, Micro services architecture has been followed for scalability of API as a service.
- c. Built reusable code and libraries for future use .
- d. Optimised the application for performance and scalability.
- e. Built Data pipelines for image storage and processing it.
- f. Participation in the team and leading in the technical issues various project life cycle and code reviewing.
- g. Working with CXO's to identify business needs,CTQ's and brainstorm on strategic initiatives.

Milestones:

- SmartRisk wins the HDFC Bank Digital Innovation Summit 2018.
- won and delivered the Product as API as service and as web application to clients In india and abroad as well.

EY (Ernest & Young GDS LLP), Software Engineer

June 2017-Feb 2018

Roles and responsibilities:

- a. Was engaged in providing automation solutions to the clients and ensuring the cost Effective of their business delivery
- b. Worked closely with software architects and consultants to develop proof -of-concepts for possibile automation scenarios.
- c. Automated the report generations for higher management through emails.
- d. Participation in SCRUM meetings and planning the tasks through CTQ prioritisation.

Infosys, Senior Systems Engineer

September 2016- May 2017

Have been part of development teams for minor and major enhancement projects. My responsibilities include

- Responsible for coding in JAVA, Python while maintaining high standards for code quality.
- For QA , testing the code and writing test scripts for automation testing.
- Talking with MNC client managers/employees for application support and maintenance issues.
- Involved in software design reviews, peer code reviews and test case reviews on a regular basis.

Infosys, Systems Engineer

September 2014- August 2016

After my college, I got into this organisation where I got trained here with all Computer science fundamentals through the Infosys campus training program.

- Attended technical and computer science course in Infosys Mysore campus.
- built a shopping cart application for project training using JAVA/J2EE.
- Written test cases and involved in bugs identification in the JAVA code.
- implemented static HTML,CSS for project enhancements.
- interacted with clients while giving demo's for project enhancement requests.

Education:

Bachelor Degree in Technology at Acharya Nagarjuna University, Guntur. 2010-2014 Major courses: Mechanical Engineering | Grade:75%